in this video we're going to talk about
entering in general journals and GP and
compare that to the experience of
entering in those same transactions in
business
Central to begin let's go to GP where
I've already created a GL batch and
entered in two different general journal
entries the first entry is for a monthly
auto insurance bill for a small Fleet of
company Vehicles we have I can see the
journal entry number the description as
well as the auto insurance expense
account and operating cash being
credited in this same batch I've also
entered in a transaction for our monthly
interest income on our savings account I
could continue to enter in more journal
entries and when complete post the
batch now let's look at business Central
and see how we can enter in those same
journal entries in general
ledger to begin I'll navigate to the
general journal window this is where we
can create and Define batches for for
our journal entries in this example the
batches are set up operationally but you
could also create batches per user if
you had multiple users entering in
transactions into general ledger for our
purposes I'll go ahead and select the
default
batch in the general journal you can see
much of that same information you did in
GP let's enter in the auto insurance
journal entry we saw in
GP because I don't always remember the
account number I can start typing the
name of the account in the in the
drop-down will automatically filter for
me I can update the description or
reference if I want more detail and then
finish filling out the rest of the
journal entry with the correct debit
amount an account being
credited next I can select to create a
new document and enter in the interest
income journal
entry however instead of entering the
next journal entry the same as we just
did let's look at another way you can
enter in journal entries in business
Central by selecting the SCH more
columns you get a slightly different
view of how you can enter in journal
entries you can see it's showing my
first document as two lines in the grid
with my debit and credit amounts you can
also enter the journal entry in a single
line
let's do that for the interest income
you can see how it's automatically
filled in the Dex document number for me
and I can start entering in the savings
account and the amount of interest
earned next I can enter in the offset
account that will automatically be
credited and this is example of a quick
and efficient way to enter in a lot of
journal entries all at
once lastly if you do have a large
journal entry you are dealing with you
can always choose to edit in Excel make
the changes and publish those back to
business
Central once the information is
populated in Excel I could easily make
mass changes if I had a large number of
lines I could copy the lines and then
edit
them in our example I'll go ahead and
make a simple change to illustrate how
to make a change and push that back into
business
Central now that the changes have been
published we'll go back into business
Central and refresh the screen to see
the
changes upon refreshing I can see that
my amount has now been updated to
$300 once all the journal entries are
entered I can select to post them and
that's a quick look at how you can
easily and efficiently ENT in journal
entries in business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources